Keeping persona's in mind when you're designing a product,
在设计产品的时候我们必须谨记自己的角色模型
how does accessibility play in the persona's?
设计无障碍功能时如何设立角色模型呢？
>> Well, like with all persona's you want those to be based on information
所有的角色模型都是
from talking to real users.
根据和真正的用户谈话得到的信息而建立的
And so again, is no different here.
这里也是一样
So you want to go out and actually talk with people that have these impairments.
所以你需要走出去和真正有缺陷的人谈话
And when you're developing your persona, some key pieces of information that you
在开发角色模型时 你需要得到的关键信息包括
want to include are, what is their impairment?
他们的缺陷是什么？
What is the severity of it?
严重性如何？
How do they kind of tackle and
他们怎么应对他们的缺陷
get through their daily challenges with the impairment?
完成每天的挑战的？
What are certain assistive technologies that they use?
他们使用哪些辅助技术？
What's or how experienced are they with those assistive technologies?
他们使用这些辅助技术有多熟练？
What's their skill level?
他们的技能水平如何？
>> Mm-hm.
恩
>> You want to talk about what are their pain points in trying
你需要和他们讨论他们在使用你的产品
to achieve tasks that are related to your product.
完成任务时有什么痛苦点？
The whole goal is just to really try to get in some important
整个目的是想要得到一些重要的信息
insights into how they go about completing tasks,
他们怎么完成任务
and what are some of their different approaches that they might take that
相比你之前聊过的其他用户
maybe other users that you've already spoken to haven't.
他们会使用哪些不同的方法
>> And what if I don't have access necessarily to someone who
如果我们没有接触到有缺陷的用户的途径
has an impairment, like who else could I contact, or how may I get that insight?
我可以联系其他哪些人 或者我如何得到相关的信息？
>> Well, you'd be surprised at because there is a wide range
你可能会觉得奇怪的
of impairments like again,
因为缺陷是个很大的范围
if somebody that has just kind of lower vision versus somebody that's completely
有的人视力较弱 有的人可能完全失明之类的
blind, you probably do know somebody with some sort of impairment.
你很可能认识有某种缺陷的人
And just thinking about an older relative maybe that
比如说 想一想身边可能视力较弱
has lost a bit of their vision or has arthritis and
或者是有关节炎以及灵敏度不及以前的
their level of dexterity isn't as what it use to be
一些老年人亲戚
that's really valuable in sites that you can talk to them about or somebody who's
实地和他们谈话是非常有价值的
not a native speaker of the language that's prominent in your app.
或者找一个母语和你的产品首要语言不同的人
They have to kind of approach things in a different way too,
他们也必须用不同的方式完成任务
that could be really insightful.
这个也很有帮助
So there's a lot of people out there that you might not
所以 有很多你一开始想不到的人
immediately consider talking to, that would be really valuable.
但最后会得到很有价值的信息
>> Great.
非常棒
What companies have you seen that have been designing for all users and
你见过哪些公司为所有用户
especially with those with impairments?
尤其是有缺陷的用户 设计产品呢？
>> So, stepping out of the digital world for
跳出数字世界
a minute, I think two great examples are the Bradley Watch, which is right here.
我想到两个很好的例子 一个是 Bradley 手表 大家这里可以看到
The Bradley Watch was designed from the get go thinking about
Bradley 手表一开始是为有缺陷
people with impairments, at least with the visual impairments in particular.
尤其是视力缺陷的人设计的
And so what this watch allows you to do is tell time
所以这种表可以让你
with just feeling the watch.
通过触摸手表感知时间
And you can see there's two magnetic balls here that indicate the hour and
你可以看这里有两个磁球分别说明时与分
the minute, and this is obviously great for
这明显能够帮助
people with disabilities in that it helps them tell the time, but
残疾人知道时间
it also is visually appealing, it's very aesthetically pleasing.
但是 同时它的外形非常有吸引力 非常美观
And it doesn't look like anything very different than other watches.
与其他的手表看上去没有什么不同
So it doesn't draw attention to their disability,
不会让人注意到佩戴者的残疾
which is always an added bonus to these types of devices.
反而是比一般手表加了分
But then just thinking about in situations where if you are sighted,
但想想某一些场景 就算你是视力健全的
you might be in a dark movie theater, or in a meeting,
你可能在黑漆漆的电影院 或者是在会议或讨论中
or discussion where you don't want to take your gaze away and
通过它 你可以不移开你的视线的同时
you want to still understand what time it is, it's really valuable.
知道时间 这是很有帮助的一点
>> Yeah, that's great.
是这样的 很棒
>> Yeah, so you can see, this is a great example of thinking about
所以 这就是一开始考虑特定需求
those needs upfront and coming up with a great product for everybody.
最后得到对所有人而言都很好的产品的典型例子
>> And the other one was Oxo.
另外一个是 Oxo
>> Yes, and so, Oxo design is that they have a whole
是的 Oxo 设计有一个致力于通用设计的设计团队
design team that focus on universal design, which we talked about before.
我们之前也有提及过
And some of their products always have,
他们的一些产品
are always keeping in mind different needs.
总是会考虑到很多不同的需求
And so some examples are, they talk about this again on their website where
比如说 他们在官网又提到
they can use a basalts bender with one hand, or
你可以上用一只手使用 basalts bender (黑色杯子)
their measuring cups are really unique, in that you don't have to kind of
他们的量杯也很独特
bend down to see where the liquid is measuring.
你不用俯身去看液体的测量值
You can look over and see where the numbers are.
你可以从上面看到那些数字
So they take a lot of things into consideration.
他们考虑了很多东西
Again, it benefits all users, not just those with disabilities.
它让所有用户都受益匪浅 不仅仅是残疾人
>> And to wrap up, what are you final thoughts on accessibility?
总结一下 你对无障碍功能最后想说什么？
>> I'd like to say that yes, it can be daunting.
我想说的是 如果在设计开发流程的最后
It can be time-consuming if it's left to the end of the design development
才来考虑这些
process.
的确会是很让人挫败很耗费时间的事情
There's always a lot of retrofitting and
如果留到最后
rethinking that needs to happen if it's left to the end.
会有很多重新改型、重新思考的地方
There's no doubt about it.
这是毋庸置疑的
So, to save everyone time and pain, think about it early.
所以 为了少用时间 减少痛苦 尽早地考虑这个问题
Think about throughout the entire process and
彻底地想一想整个过程
just incorporate it into your existing process.
然后放入当前的过程之中
And in the end, not only will you have saved time.
这样 你不仅能节约时间
But you will also come up with a much better product that's usable
你还能够制作一个所有人都能使用的
for everybody.
更加好的产品